<chapter id="install">
	<title>Installation Guide</title>
	<sect1>
		<title>System Requirements</title>
		To be able to compile and run the Java programs you must have
		the following pieces of software installed.
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<literal>Java 1.5</literal>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<literal>Ant 1.7</literal>
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Building and Testing</title>
		To compile the java programs, first extract the contents of the
		archive and place the resulting directory where you wish to
		install the program. To compile the program enter the command:
		<programlisting>$ ant build</programlisting>
		This command will ask ant to compile the program using Java. If
		the build completed successfully you will see in the command
		line output something similar to the following.
		<programlisting format="linespecific">
			<![CDATA[
BUILD SUCCESSFUL
Total time: 10 seconds
]]>
		</programlisting>
		To test the installation of the program enter the command:
		<programlisting>$ ant test</programlisting>
		This will perform a series of predefined JUnit tests that will
		assert the programs correctness. from the JUnit tests and just
		before the command prompt something similar to the following:
		<programlisting format="linespecific">
			<![CDATA[
BUILD SUCCESSFUL
Total time: 10 seconds
]]>
		</programlisting>
		More information regarding the results of the tests can be found
		in the file
		<literal>junit/report/index.html</literal>
		. For more information regarding the build commands you can use
		the following commands:
		<programlisting>$ ant -p</programlisting>
		<programlisting>$ ant usage</programlisting>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>Generating the Executables</title>
		The commands to construct the executable JAR files for each of
		the individual programs are illustrated below.
		<important>
			For the program to work successfully after installation, the
			JAR file must be kept in the same directory that it was
			created in as it depends on several libraries and files in
			that directory.
		</important>
		<sect2>
			<title>SearchSystem</title>
			To generate the executable for the SearchSystem enter the
			following command.
			<programlisting>$ ant make-jar-search</programlisting>
			This will generate a JAR file called
			<literal>CS4099_MajorSP_search.jar</literal>
			.
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>ResultsTransformer</title>
			To generate the executable for the ResultsTransformer enter
			the following command.
			<programlisting>$ ant make-jar-transform</programlisting>
			This will generate a JAR file called
			<literal>CS4099_MajorSP_transform.jar</literal>
			.
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>SearchSystem</title>
			To generate the executable for the ValidateSearch program
			enter the following command.
			<programlisting>$ ant make-jar-validate</programlisting>
			This will generate a JAR file called
			<literal>CS4099_MajorSP_validate.jar</literal>
			.
		</sect2>
		<sect2>
			<title>All Programs</title>
			To generate the executable for all the programs enter the
			following command.
			<programlisting>$ ant make-jars</programlisting>
			This will generate the JAR files for all the programs.
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
</chapter>